Balqees Sabir - Software Developer & UI UX Designer

Cairo, 11828 • (0020) 106 456 9049

balqeessaber@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/balqees-sabir-8119bb162

A Software Developer and UI/UX Designer with more than 4 years of experience in Web, Mobile applications Development and design using javascript and libraries like React, and React Native.Looking for a challenging software development environment where my technical expertise, design and intellectual skills can grow and expand.

SKILLS

- React
- React Native
- Node js
- UI UX Design
- GIT
- Illustrator / Photoshop

- HTML / CSS
- MongoDB
- ES6
- Figma
- Team work
- Self Motivated

EXPERIENCE

Eptikar IT Solutions, Sudan • Front-End developer

August 2020 - Present

- Developed and designed more than 6 websites including the company's official website.
- Created and oversaw wireframe designs from clients requests.
- Developed and designed mobile apps and helped in adding new features to existing mobile apps.
- Designed logos and brochures for the company's products and the company's profile.
- Conducted workshops and meetings to collect requirements from users.
- Conducted End-user training for more than 3 companies.

Tana Water Tanks, Sudan • Graphic designer

November 2019 - August 2020

- Designed the company profile.
- Designed brochures for the company's products.
- Increased sales through social media platforms by more than 40%.
- Designed social media content for the company.

Telekom Applied Business SDN BHD, Malaysia • Web Development intern February

February 2019 - August 2019

- Developed user interfaces with modern Javascript frameworks. HTML and CSS which improved user satisfaction by 31%.
- Performed tasks assigned by the internship supervisor efficiently.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

International Islamic University, Malaysia • Bachelor of Computer Science & Information Technology

Graduation Year (2019)

Relevant courses: Java programming language, Oracle, MySQL

Human-Computer Interaction, Operating Systems, Networks Administration,

Enterprise Networks, Cryptography.

CGPA: 3.18

International Islamic University, Malaysia • Foundation program of Computer Science & Information Technology

Graduation Year (2015)

Relevant courses: C/C++, Basic Computer Skills, HTML/CSS,

GPA of 3.36

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Sudanese students' society at IIUM

January 2016 - January 2017

Represent IIUM's Sudanese students at international events and coordinate programs and activities for the student throughout the year.

Techworks by Savannah Innovation Labs

June 2022 - August 2022

Gained technical and business development skills like programming in python, data analytics and project management.

Developed online mentoring platform using next JS and node JS, A web based platform that aims to ease access to training and hands-on experience in different fields.

It targets those who seek one to one mentoring, training, and guidance. And provides help to employees who want help with their designated tasks.

Final year project showcase

May 2019

Developed Prisoner smart watch and Management system using Java and Arduino with three main functionalities: prisoners heart rate detector, Emergency button and Geo location identifier.